Guide to the American authors collection, 1832-1956
Department of Special Collections
- HOVEY, HENRIETTA (MRS. RICHARD) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - In the Midst Thereof, signed Selah, printed poem, 1p.
  - Untitled piece, signed Selah, TMs, 1p.
- HOWE, JULIA WARD (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - To Mrs. Hecht (?), 10 Jan. 1894, ALS, 1p.
- HOWE, LOUISE C.
  SEE HENRY & ALINE HERLAND
- HOWLAND, MR.
- HUBBARD, ELBERT
- HUBBARD, MRS. S. ISABELLE
  SEE REV. SAMUEL F. SMITH
- HUDSON, HOYT H.
  SEE HOWARD VINCENT O'BRIEN, GEORGE SANTAYANA
- HUGHES, JAMES LANGSTON (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - The Negro Speaks of Rivers, printed card of his first published poem, signed, 1941, 1p.
- HUGHES, RUPERT (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - To Frederick O'Brien, 10 Nov. 1931, ALS, 1p.
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 23 July 1943, ALS, 1p.
- HULL, HELEN
- HUTCHINSON, H.E.
- HYDE, GEORGE K.
- IRVING, WASHINGTON (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - To Geo. P. Putnam, ND, ALS, lp.
    found in History of New York, by Washington Irving
  - Certificate, signed, 1857, 1p.
  - ANS, n.d., 1p.
- IRWIN, INEZ HAYNES (WIFE OF WILL IRWIN) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - To Miss Bremer, 20 Jan. 1916, ANS, lp.
  - To Anna M. Bremer, 1 Aug. 1917, ANS, lp.
- IRWIN, WALLACE
- IRWIN, WILL (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - To Rex, 25 Apr. 1939, ALS, lp.
  - To Sheridan, 1 July n.y., ALS, lp.
  - Story of Scituate. some pages typed with hand corrections, n.d., AMs, 82pp. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photograph, Will Irwin as volunteer yell leader... (Box 3, Folder 4)
- IORIO, ADRIAN J.
- JAMES, HENRY (1879-1947) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - To Canning Schiller, 24 June 1911,w/env., ALS, 3pp.
  - To F.C.S. Schiller, 24 Apr. 1912,w/env., ALS, 6pp.
  - To F.C.S. Schiller, 22 Dec. 1920,w/env., TLS, lp.
  - To F.C.S. Schiller, 16 Feb. 1921,w/env., TLS, lp.
  - To F.C.S. Schiller, 2 Nov. 1922, TLS, lp.
  - To W.R. Thayer, 4 Dec. 1920,w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - Received in a book in the De Voto Library. Book not kept. (April, 1960)
- JEFFERS, ROBINSON (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - To Margaret S. Cobb, 13 Dec. 1926,w/env., ALS, lp.
  - Life from the Lifeless, copied for Albert Bender, AMsS, lp. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Watch the lights fade, copied for Albert Bender, AMsS, lp.
  - Autograph fragment signed, with photograph of Jeffers, lp.
    Source: Albert M. Bender
  - Pelicans, Nov. 1925, AMsS, lp.
  - Gift of Albert Bender 14 Nov. 1932
- JEFFERS, UNA (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - To Lenore Franklin, 29 Apr. 1940,w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - To Lenore Franklin, 6 May 1940,w/env., ALS, 3pp.
  - To Lenore Franklin, 8 June 1940, ANS, 3pp.
  - To Leon Gelber, 24 June 1931,w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - To Leon Gelber, 9 Nov. 1931, ALS, lp.
  - To John O'Shea, 29 Oct. 1941, ALS, lp.
    Source: Lenore Franklin
  - To Mr. Van Patten, 24 Feb 1940,regarding the opening of Bender Room, ALS, 2pp.
    Source: James Hall Snell SEE ALSO CYRIL CLEMENS
- JEWETT, CHARLES TIMOTHY
- JOHNSON, MERLE
- JOHNSON, HIRAM
- JORDAN, DAVID STARR
  SEE PAUL MAERKER BRANDEN, CYRIL CLEMENS, OTTO WAHRENBERG
- KENNEDY, ARTHUR J. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - To [UNK], 24 Mar. 1949, ALS, lp.
- KENNEDY, JOHN F.
- KENNEDY, SLOAN
  SEE WALT WHITMAN
- KENNERLEY, MITCHELL
- KING, WILLIAM M.
- KNIGHT, GOODWIN J.
- [KUINAN?]
- LARCOM, LUCY (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - To Trustees, Wellesley College, 11 June 1889, ANS, lp.
- LAURENCE
  SEE JULIAN HAWTHORNE
- LE GALLIENE, RICHARD
- LEWIS, C. DAY
- LEWIS, DOROTHY THOMPSON (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - To Dr. Ray L. Wilbur, 25 Oct. 1937, TLS, lp.
    Source: R.L. Wilbur
- LEWIS, GLADYS, A. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - To Dr. Henry Van Patten, 5 Feb. 1951, TLS, lp.
  - From Nathan Van Patten, 9 Feb. 1951, TL, lp.
- LEWIS, JANET (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 14 letters to Julia Cooley Altrocchi, 1945-63
  - 1 ANS, [May 1945]
  - 1 cancelled check, 30 Oct. 1930
  - Lullaby, Dec. 1938, AMs initialed, lp. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- LINDSAY, LADY
- LINDSAY, (NICHOLAS) VACHEL (Oversize OS1, Folder 2)
  - To Paul Powell, 24 July 1916, ALS, 3pp.
    Source: Zeitlin
  - A Letter of Vachel Lindsay on the Movies, bound with above, printed brochure
    Gift of Nathan Van Patten
- LIPPMAN, WALTER (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 31 Oct. 1932w/env., TLS, lp.
- THE LITERARY AGENCY OF LONDON
- LONDON, CHARMIAN KITTREDGE
- LONGFELLOW, HENRY W. n.d., Autograph (Box 3, Folder 16)
- LOWELL, JAMES RUSSELL (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Untitled poem. 3 July 1858, AMsS, lp.
- LOWELL, LAWRENCE
- LUHAN, MABEL DODGE
- LYNDEN, FRED C.
  SEE DAVID HALBERSTAM
- MCCARTHY, THEODORE
- MACINTOSH, ROBERT W.
- MACLEISH, ARCHIBALD (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - To Harold J. Baily, 8 Nov. 1943w/env., found laid in A Time to Act, by Archibald MacLeish, ALS, 1p.
- MCPHERSON, JESSAMYN WEST (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - To Charles Gorham, [6 Jan. 1956]w/env., ALS, 2pp.
- MANTZ, RUTH ELVISH (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - To Kate Felton Elkins, 27 Feb. 1932w/env., TLS, 2pp.
  - To Mrs. K.F. Elkins, 5 Aug. 1932w/env., ALS, 2pp.
- MARKHAM, EDWIN (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - To Mabel Charlotte Ashley, 4 Nov. 1908,w/env. & postage stamp-sized newspaper photo of Markham, ALS, 1p.
  - To Henry Meade Bland, 1 Sept. 1928, TLS, 5pp.
    Source: Albert Bender
  - Lincoln, the Man of the People, broadside signed, 1933, 1p. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Source: Alma Lowry Williams
  - Lincoln, the Man of the People, broadside signed, 1935, 1p.
  - The Man with the Hoe, broadside signed, 23 Apr. 1936
  - An Ode to Boston, with handwritten corrections, 11 Oct. 1931, pamphlet signed
  - Outwitted, 11 June 1915, AMsS, 1p.
  - To You, 16 Dec. 1916, AMsS, 1p.
    Gift of Albert Bender
  - A Word for Mother's Day, 1 May 1934, AMsS, 2pp.
  - ANS, 1p., July 1931
  - ANS, 1p., July 1931
  - Photograph with autograph note to Jesse Lilienthal, Dec. 1928 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- MASON, WALT
- MATTHEWS, ELKIN
- MATTHIESSEN, F.O.
- MAXWELL, PERRITON
- MAYNARD
- MILLER, HENRY (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - To friend, 1 Dec. 1945,regarding George Dibbern's Quest, TL, 1p.
- MILLER, JOAQUIN (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - For Mrs. Stanford, Mar. 1872, AMsS, 1p.
  - The Life of Andrew Carnegie, Gift of Mrs. Helen S. Rapely, ATMs, 200pp. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Photograph, with on verso, ANS (Box 3, Folder 27)
- MITCHELL, EDWIN V.
- MITCHELL, RUTH COMFORT (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 19 Oct. [1920]w/env., TLS, 1p.
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 5 Sept. 1929w/env., TLS with handwritten note, 1p.
  - To Very dear Friend, 27 Sept. 1944, TLS, 1p.
- MIX, MRS. A.J. (KATHERINE)
- MOFFAT, YARD & CO.
- MONDALE, WALTER F.
- MOOREHOUSE, LEE
- MOORLY, THEO M.
- MORELEY, CHRISTOPHER
- MORTBY, EDWARD A.
- MOSHER, THOMAS B.
- MUNSON, J. JOHN
- MUNTZ, LAURA
- MURRAY, MRS. WOODWORTH NORTHEY
- MUSSOLINI, BENITO
- NASH, EDGARS
- NASH, J.H.
- NEWTON, A. EDWARD (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - To Guy Barker, 9 Oct. 1931,with magazine photograph of sender (?) attached., TLS, 1p.
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, 7 Mar. 1931, TLS, 1p.
- NORRIS, FRANK (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - A San Francisco Afternoon, 25 Mar. 1895, AMsS, 1p.
    Source: Newbegin SEE ALSO JACK O'CONNOR
- NORRIS, MRS.
  SEE IDA MINERVA TARBELL
- O'BRIEN, FRED
  SEE WITTER BYNNER
- O'BRIEN, FREDERICK
  SEE FRANK HARRIS, RUPERT HUGHES, LLOYD OSBOURNE
- O'BRIEN, HOWARD VINCENT (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - To Hoyt H. Hudson, 27 Mar. 1933w/env., TLS, 1p.
    Source: Estate of Dr. H. Hudson
    [UNK]
- O'CONNOR, JACK (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - To Mr. [Charles] Norris, 19 Aug. 1930, TLS, 1p.
    Source: Hudson Collection of Minor Poets (?)
- O'DONOVAN, MICHAEL (AND MRS. HARRIET O'DONOVAN) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - To Mr. [Wallace] Stegner, 15 Apr. 1955,signed Frank O'Connor (pseud.), TLS, 1p.
  - To Mr. [Wallace] Stegner, 17 May 1955,signed Harriet O'Connor (pseud.), TLS, 1p.
- OLDER, FREMONT (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Easter Island, 19 Feb. 1935, AMsS, 7pp.
    Gift of Albert Bender, 5/20/1940
- ONDERDONK, JUDY
- O'NEILL, CARLOTTA MONTEREY (MRS. EUGENE) (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - To Kate Felton Elkins, 13 Apr. 1932w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - To Kate Felton Elkins, 21 Apr. 1932w.env., ALS, 1p.
  - To Kate Felton Elkins, 21 Mar. 1933w/env., ALS, 3pp.
- O'NEILL, EUGENE (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - To Mrs. K.F. Elkins, 5 Jan. 1931w/env., ALS, 1p.
- O'NEILL, EUGENE (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - To Carlotta, 23 Apr. 1931, facsimile of AMsS
- O'NEILL, EUGENE (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Dynamo, galley proofs, 25 Feb. n.y., 109pps.
- ORCUTT, WILLIAM D.
- JAMES R. OSGOOD & CO.
- O'SHEA, JOHN (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Postal Telegraph, Monterey, CA to Miss Lenore Franklin, Stanford, 19 Apr. 1936
    SEE ALSO UNA JEFFERS, CHARLES ERSKINE SCOTT WOOD
- OSBOURNE, LLOYD (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - To Frederick [O'Brien], 30 Oct. 1920, TLS, 1p.
- OSSOLI, SARAH MARGARET FULLER (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - To Georgiana [Bruce], 22 Oct. 1844, ALS, 4pp.
- OWENS, WILLIAM
  SEE STEWART EDWARD WHITE
- PAIMER, WILLIAM KIMBERLEY (Oversize OS2, Folder 1)
  Common-place book containing ms. and broadside poems by Palmer; also contains 38 letters to Palmer among which are:
  - From Josephus Daniels, 29 Dec. 1934, TLS, 1p.
  - From Lawrence Lowell, 24 Apr. 1936, TLS, 1p.
  - From Franklin D. Roosevelt, 12 Dec. 1932, TLS
- PANSY
  SEE ALDEN, MRS. ISABELIA MACDONALD
- PARNIE, ELAINE HELMER (MRS. ALEXANDER) AND HAROLD HELMER (Box 3, Folder 42)
  To Elaine Helmer Parnie:
  - From Joseph Ausland, 29 Aug. 1950, TLS, 1p.
  - From Gordon Craig, 27 Dec. 1900, ALS, 2pp.
  - From Gordon Craig, [27 Aug.], n.y., ALS, 2pp.
  - From John Erskine, 19 Oct. 1929,w/env., TLS, 1p.
  - From Edmund Gosse, The Poet and the Crickett, n.d., AMsS, 5pp.
  - From Robert Cortes Holliday; [20 Dec.], 1928,w.env., printed card, 1p.
  - From Robert Cortes Holliday, 19 Oct. 1929, printed TLS, 1p.
  - From Helen Hull, 31 July 1930, TLS, 1p.
  - From Christopher Morley, 24 Sept. 1950, TNS
  - From Mildred Walker Schemm [?], 2 Apr. 1934, ALS, 2pp.
  - From M. Schwartz, 11 June 1934, TLS, 2pp.
  - From H. Allen Smith, [12 July 1946], ANS
    To Mr. Harold Helmer:
  - From E.B. Bird, 28 Dec. 1904, ALS, 1p.
  - From Earnest Elmo Calkins, 30 Dec. 1901, TLS, 1p.
  - From Robert W. Chambers, n.d., ALS, 1p.
  - From Gordon Craig, n.d., ALS, 2pp.
  - From S.A. Crockett, 6 Jan. 1902, ALS, 2pp.
  - From Theo. L. DeVinne, 26 Dec. 1901, ALS 2pp.
  - From William Ellis, 31 Dec. 1901, TLS, 2pp.
  - From Edmund Gosse, 4 Aug. 1901, ALS, 2pp.
  - From Edmund Gosse, 23 Aug. 1901, ALS, 3pp.
  - From Maurice Hewlett, 7 Jan. 1902w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - From Elbert Hubbard, 26 Dec. 1901, TLS, 1p.
  - From Elbert Hubbard, 7 Apr. 1902, TLS, 1p.
  - From H.E. Hutchinson, 7 Jan. n.y., ALS, 4pp.
  - From Adrian J. Iorio, 9 Feb. 1902, ALS, 1p.
  - From Robert W. MacIntosh, n.d., ALS, 3pp.
  - From Lee Moorehouse, 8 Oct. 1901, TLS, 2pp.
  - From Thomas B. Mosher, 30 Dec. 1901, ALS, 2pp.
  - From Theo. M. Moorly [?], ALS, 2pp.
  - From Laura Muntz, 7 Dec. 1901, ALS, 1p.
  - From Laura Muntz, 29 Dec. 1901clipping attached, ALS, 3pp.
  - From Edgar S. Nash, 3 Jan. 1902, ALS, 1p.
  - From William D. Orcutt, 27 Feb. 1902, TLS, 1p.
  - From Will H. Ransom, 26 Sept. 1901, ALS, 2pp.
  - From Ralph Fletcher Seymour, 11 Dec. 1901, ALS, 1p.
  - From Ralph Fletcher Seymour, 11 Dec. n.y., ALS, 1p.
  - From Ralph Fletcher Seymour, 24 Dec. n.y., ALS, 1p.
  - From Wilbur M. Stone, 26 Dec. 1901, ALS, 2pp.
  - From William Watson, 26 Dec. 1901,w/env., ANS, 1p.
  - From Edward A. Mortby (?), 12 Sept. 1902, ALS, 3pp.
    To Niagara Mills Paper Co.:
  - From William Ellis, 31 Dec. 1901, ALS, 2pp.
  - From Joseph W. Harper, 31 Dec. 1901, ALS, 1p.
  - To Crowninshield from Richard Le Galliene, Sunday, n.d., ANS, 1p.
  - To Mr. Parnie from Edwin V. Mitchell, 3 May 1934, ALS, 1p.
  - To Mr. Parnie from Edward E. Winchell, 28 Dec. 1901, ALS, 1p.
- PATCHEN, KENNETH (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - To Mr. Terry Bender, 3 July 1956, ALS, 1p.
- PEARSON, EDWARD R. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - To Mrs. William P. Redington, 23 Nov. 1923(w./env.), TLS, 1p.
  - To Mrs. William P. Redington, 27 May 1924, ALS, 1p.
    Found in RBCR Z992.P36. Pearson, Books in Black or Red.
- PERKINS, WILLIAM RUFUS (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - The Ideal Translation from Schiller-May-1886, AMs, 5pp.
  - Lines written in Sept. 1888, AMsS
  - Prelude, TMS with hand notations, 113pp.
  - [Untitled], Oct. or Sept. 1888,w/env., AMsS, 2pp.
  - [Untitled], AMs, 1p.
  - [Untitled], w/env., AMs, 1p.
- PERRY, BLISS
- PERSHING, JOHN J.
- PETERS, ROLLO
  SEE JOHN COOPER POWYS
- PHILLIPS, PROFESSOR U.B.
  SEE GAMALIEL BRADFORD
- PIATT, SARAH (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - My neighbour's King n.d.found in Mrs. S.M.B. Piatt, A Voyage to the Fortunate Isles.
- PILCHER, J. MITCHEL (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - To Nina Almond, 4 Sept. 1937, TLS, 1p.
  - Whip-poor-will's shoes, n.d., TMs, 1p.
  - Typed publication announcement, for the Paebar Anthology of Verse., 1p.
    Source: J.M. Pilcher
- POLLACK, CHANNING (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - To Perriton Maxwell, 2 July 1928, TLS, 1p.
  - To Miss Garvin from Mayson L. Beeton (?), 16 Nov. 1929.Found in Channing Pollack, Harvest of Years., ALS, 2pp.
- PORTER, WILLIAM SYDNEY (O.HENRY) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - To Bro. [George B.] Baker, Saturday, n.d., ALS, 2pp.
  - To [Mrs. W.P. Fuller, Jr.] from George B. Baker, regarding O.Henry, 15 Apr. 1927, TLS, 3pp.
    Gift of Mrs. W. Palmer Fuller
- POWELL, PAUL
  SEE (NICHOLAS) VACHEL LINDSAY
- POUND, EZRA (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - To Charlotte, 24 July 1911 (?), ALS, 4pp.
  - To Charlotte, 30 July n.y., ALS, 2pp.
  - To Charlotte, n.d., ALS, 1p.
  - To Charlotte, n.d., ALS, 3pp.
  - To Charlotte, n.d., ALS, 4pp.
  - To E.E. Cummings, 14 Apr. n.y., ANS, 1p.
  - To Horatio and Gloria, n.d., ALS, 4pp.
  - To P.C. de M., n.d., ALS, 2pp.
  - To P.C. de M., n.d., ALS, 4pp.
  - To P.C. de M., n.d., ALS, 4pp.
  - To P.C. de M., n.d., ALS, 7pp.
  - To P.C. de M., n.d., ALS, 1pp.
  - To Elkin Matthews, [8 Mar. 1910], ANS, 1p.
  - To Elkin Matthews, [18 Mar. 1910],w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - To J. John Munson, 14 Apr. n.y., ANS, 1p.
  - To Edtr. Forum, 8 Feb. 1928, TLS, 1p.
  - To (?), n.d., ALS, 2pp.
  - To Mr. Smith, 11 Dec. 1914, TLS
    Source: Emily Driscoll, N.T. Mss dealer, Nov. 1954
- POWYS, JOHN COOPER (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - To Will Solle, n.d.Found in Powys, John Cooper, Weymouth Sands, Leventritt gift., ALS, 3pp.
  - From Rollo Peters, 1 Sept. [1918], ALS, 3pp.
  - From Rollo Peters, [16 Oct. 1918], ALS, 4pp.
- PRINDERVILLE (Oversize OS3, Folder 1)
  - To Mrs. M. Wells, 22 Nov. 1931., ALS, 1p.
    In: History and methods of writing, AMsS, bound, approx 60pp.
    Source: author?
- PUMPELLY, GEORGE I.
  SEE NATHANIEL PARKER WILLIS
- PUTNAM, GEO. P.
  SEE WASHINGTON IRVING
- RANCK, T.V.
  SEE PAUL MAERKER BRANDEN, HENRY P. BURTON
- RANSOM, WILL H.
- REDING, MRS. WILLIAM P.
  SEE EDWARD R. PEARSON
- REDPATH, JAMES
  SEE CHARLES DUDLEY-WARNER
- REX
  SEE WILL IRWIN
- REYNOLDS, L.
- RICE, CALE YOUNG
- RIIS, JACOB (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - To Helen B. Sutliff, 3 Nov. 1902,w/env.
    Gift of Helen B. Sutliff
- RILEY, JAMES WHITCOMB (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - to Stanton, 28 Apr. 1898, ALS, 1p.
    Source: K.F. Elkins
- ROBERTS, DONALD A.
  SEE HENRY AND ALINE HARLAND
- ROBERTSON, GEORGE & CO.
- ROOSEVELT, FRANKLIN D.
- ROURKE, CONSTANCE
- ROYCE, JOSIAH (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - To Miss Hecht, 27 Dec. 1891, ALS, 2pp.
- SANBORN, FRANKLIN BENJAMIN (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - To [Ralph Waldo Emerson], 10 May 1859, ALS, 2pp.
  - To [Ralph Waldo Emerson], 16 Mar. 1869, ALS, 4pp.
  - To [Ralph Waldo Emerson], 29 Dec. 1873, ALS, 4pp.
- SANCHEZ, NELLIE V. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - To Mr. Clemens, 6 May 1929, TNS, 1p.
    Source: Nathan van Patten
- SANDBURG, CARL
- SANTAYANA, GEORGE (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - To Hoyt H. Hudson, 4 Nov. 1930w/env., ALS, 1p.
  - Untitled sonnet, Feb. 1911,reproduced on postcard directed to Julius Barclay
    Gift of Judy Onderdonk [?]
- SAROYAN, WILLIAM (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - To Valenti Angelo, 22 Aug. 1949, TLS, 1p.
  - To Valenti Angelo, 3 Sept. 1949, TLS, 1p.
  - To Valenti Angelo, 26 Sept. 1949, TLS, 1p.
    Source: Chiswick Book Shop, New York
  - To Charles R. Gorham, 6 Aug. 1955, TLS, 1p.
  - From Charles R. Gorham, autograph, 2 Aug. 1955n.d., TLS, 1p.
    Source: Chiswick Book Shop
  - The Fiscal Hoboes: a short story, 22 Aug. 1949, TMs with hand corrections (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newsclip A Message from William Saroyan... (Oversize OS3, Folder 2)
    Photocopy of above item reduced
  - Newsclip A Message from William Saroyan to the moving picture manufacturers, Variety, 6 Aug. 1941
    Source: Mr. Jack Sheridan
- SCHEFFAEUR, HERMAN GEORGE (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Half a league-half a league-, TMsS with hand corrections, 19pp.
- SCHEMM, MILDRED WALKER
- SCHILLER, F.C.S.
  SEE HENRY JAMES
- SCHLESINGER, ARTHUR, JR. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bernard De Voto and public affairs, n.d., TMs, 32pp.
- SCHWARTZ, M.
- SEYMOUR, RALPH FLETCHER
- SHAW, GEORGE BERNARD
- SHAW, HENRY WHEELER (JOSH BILLINGS) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Printed card, signed on verso by Josh Billings n.d.
- SHULENBERGER, ARVID (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - To Yvor Winters, 12 Feb. 1955w/env., TLS, 1p.
- SIGOURNEY, LYDIA HOWARD (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Prayers for one gone to sea [1844], AMsS, 1p.
- SINCLAIR, UPTON (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence (outgoing), 1907, (9 letters)
    Correspondents include: Perris & Casenove, The Literary Agency of London, Heinemann,
  - Correspondence (outgoing), 1908, (25 letters) (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Correspondents include: Perris & Casenove, The Literary Agency of London, Robert S. Yard,
  - Correspondence (outgoing), 1909, (19 letters) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Correspondents include: Perris & Casenove, The Literary Agency of London
  - Correspondence (outgoing), 1910, (21 letters) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Correspondents include: Perris & Casenove
  - Correspondence (incoming), 1910, (26 letters) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Correspondents include: George Robertson & Co., Moffat, Yard & Co., Mitchell Kennerley
  - Correspondence (outgoing), 1911, (25 letters) (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Correspondents include: Perris & Casenove, Wm. Heinemann
  - Correspondence (outgoing), 1911, (25 letters) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Correspondents
  - Correspondence (outgoing), 1911, (20 letters) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence (incoming), 1912, (18 letters) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Correspondents unidentified:
  - Correspondence (outgoing), 1913, 1914, (27 letters) (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Correspondents include: Casenove, Literary Agency of London, (incoming), John C. Winston Co.
  - To Manchester Boddy, 17 June 1935 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - To Manchester Boddy, 19 June 1935
  - To Cyril clemens, 2 June 1936
    10 miscellaneous items Source: Marshall Field, 1 Mar. 1938 SEE ALSO CYRIL CLEMENS
- SLOSS, MRS. M.C. & MR.
  See GERTRUDE ATHERTON, JOSEPH AUSLANDER, WILLAIM ROSE BENET, PEARL S. BUCK, JOHN BURTON, INA DONNA COOLBRITH, RACHEL FIELD, JOHN GOULD FLETCHER, MARY ANTIA GRABAU, RUPERT HUGHED, WALTER LIPPMAN, RUTH COMFORT MITCHELL, A. EDWARD NEWTON, GERTRUDE STEIN, KATE DOUGIAS WIGGINS, WILLIAM WINTERS
- SMITH, CLARK ASHTON (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Chant to Sirius, n.d., Ams, lp.
  - The Hashish-Eater n.d., TMs with hand corrections, 11p.
  - The Nereid n.d., AMsS, 2pp.
- SMITH, H. ALLEN
- SMITH, MR.
- SMITH, REV. SAMUEL F. (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - To Mrs. S. Isabelle Hubbard, 23 Sept. 1892,w/env., ALS, lp.
  - To Mrs. Leland Stanford from S. Isabelle Hubbard, 12 Dec. 1894, ALS, lp.
  - America, 10 Sept. 1892, AMsS, lp.
    Gift of S. Isabelle Hubbard to Stanford Museum
- SOLLE, WILL
- STANFORD, MRS. LELAND
  SEE SAMUEL CLEMENS, CHARLES K. FIELD, REV. SAMUEL F. SMITH, JOAQUIN MILLER
- STANTON
  SEE JAMES WHITCOMB RILEY
- STARRETT, VINCENT (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - To [Nathan] van Patten, 18 Jan. 1939, ALS, lp.
  - To [Nathan] van Patten, 13 Mar. 1939, ALS, lp.
- STEDMAN, EDMUND C. (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - To William Winter, 16 Jan. 1895, ALS, lp.
  - To [John] Hay, 31 Dec. 1903, ALS, 2pp.
- STEELE, JAMES KING (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Manila Mixture, a Philippine heritage a saga of mixed bloods, n.d.[copyright 1936], pp. 1-115, TMS with hand corrections, 137 leaves (including 18 photos)
    Source: Gift of Mr. Short Steele in memory of James King Steele
  - Manila Mixture, n.d.[copyright 1936], pp. 116-246 TMS with hand corrections, 215 leaves (including 16 photos) (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Manila Mixture, pp. 247-312 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    Source: Gift of Mr. Short Steele
  - Manila Melody, n.d.[copyright 1936], pp. 1-126. TMs (carbon), 130 leaves (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Manila Melody, n.d.[copyright 1936], pp. 127-312. TMs (carbon), 186 leaves (Box 5, Folder 2)
- STEELE, MARTIN
  SEE OLIVER W. HOLMES
- STEFFENS, LINCOLN (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - To Dr. Ray Lyman Wilbur, 12 Apr. 1918, ALS, lp.
  - To Dr. Ray Lyman Wilbur, 14 Apr. 1918, ANS
    Source: Dr. Ray Lyman Wilbur
- STEGNER, WALLACE
  SEE CYRIL CLEMENS, RICHARD MARTIN STERN, MICHAEL O'DONOVAN
- STEIN, GERTRUDE (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - To Mrs. [Max] Sloss, [17 Apr. 1935],w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - 3 inscriptions, signed., lp.
- STEINBECK, JOHN (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - To Leon Gelber, [15 Aug. 1940],w/env., ALS, lp.
- STERLING, J.E. WALLACE
- STERN, RICHARD MARTIN (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - From Richard Martin Stern, 31 July 1961, TLS, lp.
  - To [Wallace] Stegner, 23 Jan. 1962, TLS, lp.
  - From Carl Brandt, [Dec. 1956], ALS, 4pp.
  - From Wallace Stegner, 16 Jan. 1962, TL (carbon), lp.
    Source: Richard Martin Stern
  - The Violent Road [published as The Bright Road to Fear] n.d., TMs with hand corrections by Carl Brandt, pp. 1-165 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Violent road, pp.165-265 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Source: Gift of Richard Martin Stern
- STILWELL, WINIFRED
- STODDARD, CHARLES WARREN (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - [Bound Ms journal] May 14-June 17; Oct. 28-Oct. 31 1905
  - [Bound Ms journal] vol. I June 28-July 2 1905
  - [Bound Ms journal] Vol. II July 3-July 9 1905
  - [Bound Ms journal] Vol. III July 10-July 11 1905
    SEE ALSO SAMUEL CLEMENS
- STONE, WILBUR M.
- STOWE, HARRIET BEECHER [copy of Psalm 107:8-9], 2 Apr. 1885, AMsS (Box 5, Folder 10)
- SUTLIFF, HELEN B.
  SEE JACOB RIIS
- SWANK, RAYNARD C.
  SEE JACOB BLANCK, BRUCE BLIVEN
- TAGGARD, GENEVIEVE (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hawaiian Hilltops including poems, TMs, 6 leaves
  - Kanaka Mother-Goose, Native Daphne and The Tourist, 1923
  - [Hawaiian Hilltops], Galley proofs with hand corrections. n.d., 13 leaves
- TARBELL, IDA MINERVA (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - To Mrs. Norris, 7 Mar. n.y., ALS, 1p.
- TAYLOR, BAYARD (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - To Ticknor, 16 Apr. 1866, ANS
    Source: Kate Felton Elkins
  - Autograph [cut from letter]
- TAYLOR, EDWARD ROBESON (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Waiting [1917?], AMsS
- TAYLOR, REBECCA W. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - [Untitled poem], 27 Sept. 1881(also signed by Joseph Taylor), AMsS, 1p.
- THAYER, W.R.
- TICKNOR
  SEE BAYARD TAYLOR
- TOKIAS, ALICE B. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - To Mr. Wilson, 17 Apr. 1935, TNS
- TRAUBEL, HORACE (Oversize OS3, Folder 3)
  Bound volume of 39 ALS to Henriette Hovey, including:
  - 25 Apr. 1901, 1p.
  - 27 May 1901, 1p.
  - 30 May 1901, 1p.
  - 20 May 1901, 1p.
  - 6 June 1901, 1p.
  - 12 June 1901, 1p.
  - 30 June 1901, 1p.
  - 14 July 1901, 1p.
  - 11 Aug. 1901, 1p.
  - 23 Aug. 1901, 1p.
  - 12 Sept. 1901, 1p.
  - 27 Sept. 1901, 1p.
  - 20 Oct. 1901, 1p.
  - 25 Oct. 1901, 1p.
  - 26 Nov. 1901, 1p.
  - 5 Dec. 1901, 1p.
  - 30 Dec. 1901, 1p.
  - 15 Jan. 1902, 1p.
  - 21 Jan. 1902, 1p.
  - 5 Feb. 1902, 1p.
  - 12 Mar. 1902, 1p.
  - 11 Apr. 1902, 1p.
  - 24 Apr. 1902, 1p.
  - 19 May 1902, 1p.
  - 21 May 1902, 1p.
  - 25 May 1902, 1p.
  - 26 May 1902, 1p.
  - 27 May 1902, 1p.
  - 8 Sept. 1902, 1p.
  - 20 Oct. 1902, 1p.
  - 27 Feb. 1903, 1p.
  - 2 Apr. 1903, 1p.
  - 24 Apr. 1903, 1p.
  - 6 May 1903, 1p.
  - 20 May 1903, 1p.
  - 9 Oct. 1903, 1p.
  - 24 May 1903, 1p.
  - 17 June 1903, 1p.
  - 27 June 1903, 1p.
  - Printed Poem The Christ of the Crater, from The Conservator, with ms note to Henriette Hovey and signature, 2pp. (Box 5, Folder 17)
- TWAIN, MARK
- TWAIN, RUPERT
- VAN DOREN, CARL (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - To [Nathan] van Patten, 27 June 1948, TLS, 1p.
- VAN PATTEN
  SEE GERITRUDE ATHERTON
- VAN PATTEN, DR. HENRY
  SEE GLADYS A. LEWIS
- VAN PATTEN, NATHAN